

JOAN S. PONS

UX Research · Product Design

CONTACT

janisaez@gmail.com +44(0)7955858749 https://joans.work

SPOTLIGHT

I am a passionate, enthusiastic UX researcher and product designer with programming skills and academic background who enjoys working in a challenging environment. I embrace user feedback and usage data to help the business by balancing the user experience strategy and business goals. I am comfortable both leading and working in a multidisciplinary and international team, constantly striving to improve and best of all have fun!

EXPERIENCE

Principal UI/UX Designer, Clarivate, London, UK

SEP 19 - PRESENT

Senior UX Designer, Clarivate Analytics, London, UK

FEB 18 - SEP 19

Post-doc at Birckbeck University, London, UK

FEB 18 - FEB 19

Lead Developer at Birckbeck University, London, UK

MAY 17 - DEC 17

Software Developer and UX Designer at Retechnica, London, UK

AUG 2015 - NOV 2017

HCI Post-doc at University of Hertfordshire, Hatfield, UK

DEC 2012 - MAY 2015

HCI Post-doc at BarcelonaTech (UPC), Barcelona, Spain.

MAY 2010 - DEC 2011

Research Assistant at Sheffield Hallam University, Sheffield, UK

APR 2007 - MAY 2010

MARIE-CURIE fellowship at Eberhard Karls University, Tübingen, Germany

MAY 2004 - APR 2007

EDUCATION

PHD in Robotics at Sheffield Hallam University, Sheffield, UK

MAY 2007- SEP 2010

MSC Automatics and Control Engineering at Rovira i Virgili University, Tarragona, Spain SEP 2001 - JUN 2003

BENG in Industrial Electronics Engineering at at Rovira i Virgili University, Tarragon, Spain SEP 1997 - SEP 2000

TOOLSET

Workshops: Mural, Freehand, Miro Analytics: Pendo, GA, Tableau

Prototyping: Sketch, Axure, Marvel, Balsamiq Hand-off systems: Invision, Zeplin, Abstract Product Ops: Pendo, Amplitude, Enjoyhq

Testing: Maze, UserZoom

Other: Airtable, Notion, Abstract, Typeform

OTHER

Over 40+ scientific articles published in journals, international conferences and workshops with 450+ citations.

Member of Leaders of Awesomeness community by Jared Spool, completed intensive courses, i.e. Advanced Approaches to UX Research, Experience Vision.

Clarivate First Mile - New Leader Program, Issued by Harvard Business Publishing Corporate Learning.

Fluent in English (ACE), Catalan and Spanish language. German, Level B, 1.1.

SOFT SKILLS

Ability to efficiently and clearly communicate ideas.

Ability to reliably plan and estimate development time requirements.

Capacity of putting out fires in startups environments.

Continuously challenge and teach myself in personal projects.

Comfortable with abrupt change to project deadlines and the local gravity field.